ZIA



💡 Vårlöksgatan 2C, 41706 GÖTEBORG

- 0046-72-121 71 74 🗎 0046-76-988 57 45

zia_gt@yahoo.com

DOB: 1985-03-13

LinkedIn: https://se.linkedin.com/in/zia-ullah

GitHub: https://github.com/ziaongit *Fiverr:* https://www.fiverr.com/ziacanic

Summary:

Web developer with extensive experience in web design and web development. Dedicated, responsible, team player, hardworking and fast learner with a knack for problem solving. Have worked both independently and in a team for agile development of company products.

Skills

Web development: HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, LESS/SASS, Bootstrap, Foundation, Materialize CSS, Kendo UI, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, JSON, Grunt/Gulp, MEAN (Mongo, ExpressJS, AngularJS, Nood), HTML5 Graphics (Canvas, SVG, Icon, Google Map), CMS (WordPress, Drupal, and Joomla)

Graphics Design Skills: Adobe Photoshop CS6, Adobe illustrator CC 2015, Adobe Fireworks CCS6,

Typography Skills, Print Design, Layout /Conversion Optimization Skills, Color

Theory

Programming languages: PHP (Procedural and OOP), C

Database: MySQL, MongoDB

Programming IDEs: IntelliJ, Eclipse, Visual Studio, and PhpStorm

SEO: On-Page SEO (Internal linking, Anchor text, Headlines, Titles and Meta tags, XML

Sitemap, Navigation, Comments, Content, Regularity, Length, Improving click through rates, Meta description research, Authorship, Schema mark-up, Images), Off-page SEO (link building, Social media, Keyword research, Google ad words,

Directories)

Other: Windows OS, Unix/Linux, Git, XML, Rest API, Scrum.

Proiects

- *Map Observer*: Icomera desktop application (Single page application)
 - My concern: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Less, Bootstrap, Working with rest API
- · Lager books: Books library management system (www.lagerbooks.com)
 - Technologies: OOP PHP, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, CSS, Less, Bootstrap 3
- · Article Management System: Designed and Developed IT Articles Management website
 - · Technologies: PHP, PhpMySQL, Adobe Photoshop, Dreamviewer
- · Car App: Car reaping management system
 - Technologies: OOP PHP, HTML, JavaScript, jOuery, CSS, Bootstrap 3
- Content Management System (CMS) projects
 - http://www.ericsbo.se/
 - http://chivasburger.com/
 - http://www.avilasenvironmental.com/
 - http://zoticon.solutions/
 - http://www.fiestapalaceballroom.com/
 - http://plumbing-diagnostics.com/

Professional experience

Period: October 2016 – February 2017 Company: Icomera AB - Gothenburg, Sweden

Position: Front-end Developer

Responsibilities:

• Developing frontend GUI for in house applications

- Developing solutions that take advantage of available APIs and customer integrations
- Developing customer-specific portals
- Develop, enhance and implement tests for Icomera solutions and development work.

Technologies: HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3 (Bootstrap, LESS/SASS), JavaScript, JQuery, PHP (Procedural OOP), and Rest API (MEAN Stack)

Period: January 2010 - Present Freelance World Network Ltd

Clients: Heavy Graphics Marketing (USA), Somit AB (Sweden), Bluekong Networks (UK)

Position: Web developer/Designer, Social Media Manager, Field Network Engineer

Responsibilities:

Web Design/Development

- Social media and Email marketing
- SEO (On-Page, Off-Page, Keyword Research, Google Ad words)
- Network Support and installation
- Providing support for Windows, Linux issues

Period: March 2009 – August 2010

Company: Sampotek Webzone Inc. - Peshawar, Pakistan

Position: Web Developer/Designer

Responsibilities:

- Graphics Design
- Frontend/Backend PHP, JavaScript, CSS scripting
- · Implementing jQuery and Ajax solutions
- CURL scripting for crawling data

Education and Training

Master (2011 - 2014): Master in Computer and System Sciences

Institution: Stockholm University (Sweden)

Bachelor (2005 - 2009): Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Institution: Gomal University (Pakistan)

COA (2009 – 2010): Web Development and Design

Institution: IT Switchers (Pakistan)

MCSE (2009 – 2010): Microsoft Certified System Engineering

Institution: IT Switchers (Pakistan)

Activities and interests

Watching movies, blogging, stacksoverflow, computer games, cricket and fitness.

Languages

English (advanced), Swedish (conversational), Urdu (advance), Pashto (advance)